# NISHANT NALWADE

· +91-9971062831

1796nishant@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/nishantnalawade/ https://nishantnalawade.github.io/Nishant.io/

## ABOUT MYSELF

I have 3.5+yrs of Experience with SAP Working on UI5, ABAP, OData, CDS, START, Fiori, and Java. In the Span of 3.5yrs, I have worked on 5 different production projects and 3 POC projects. I'm Currently in Pursuing MTech (last semester) from BITS Pilani in Software Engineering.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **NOV 2019 TO PRESENT**

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER, ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER**

Project- SAP Transportation Management.

Learnt Skills- Sap UI5, ABAP, FIORI, OData, Gateway Service, HANA CDS.

Worked on-

- Building Collaboration Portal for Manufacturer based on ABAP CDS and UI5
- Building Custom actions on Smart UI5 templates
- Updating Manage Freight Agreement Apps based on Web-Dynpro technology

## **AUGUST 2019 TO OCTOBER 2019**

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER, SCHOLAR PHASE 4**

Project-Legal Content Assemble.

Learnt Skills- Sap UI5, spring basics.

Worked on-

- Audit logging
- Adding features in UI

# **JULY 2018 TO JULY 2019**

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER, SCHOLAR PHASE 2 AND 3

Project- Big data Margin Assurance.

Learnt Skills- Sap UI5, Java, OData, Alexa, Node.js.

Worked on-

- POC for Integrating Alexa with product.
- Contributed to Innovation Dashboard.
- Stellar Awards 2019 and developed apps for Innvent-2019.
- Worked on POC for CV creation and successfully integrated with the product.
- Worked on dynamic help link creation for the product.

#### **SEPTEMBER 2017 TO APRIL 2018**

# **AUTOMATION / UI5 DEVELOPER, SCHOLAR PHASE 1**

Project-S4HANA EPPM

Learnt Skills- Sap UI5, START.

Worked on-

- 3<sup>rd</sup> Screen For our Billing application.
- Bug Fix in UI for code understanding.
- Automating all the Testing and reducing the QA test Using START Tool.

#### **MAY 2018 TO JUNE 2018**

# **DEVELOPER, INNOVISION 2018**

**Project- Connected Goods** 

Learnt Skills- SAP UI5, Cordova, Java

Worked on-

- Creating a portable demo for the team, which can be shipped anywhere and help the customer to understand how it works.
- Create mobile apps for onboarding and offboarding the customer device.

#### **JUNE 2016 TO AUGUST 2016**

# **DEVELOPER (INTERN), IITD (INTERN)**

Prototyping of a smart product to make basic consumer air-conditioners more useful and efficient.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Peer Award 2020 DSC Significant contribution and excellent performance
- Star Award 2018 PSUT ICD for Contribution in the team.
- **Zonal Winner** at NNSC (National Networking and Security Championship)
- National Competitor for networking and security competition IIT-Kanpur.
- Honor award from VT's for onboarding on Scholar Batch 2018.

# **SKILLS**

- UI5 (Freestyle and Template based), Git, Java, OData, Fiori, CDS, START, Alexa, Node.js, Cordova
- Team Work, Creativity, Adaptable.

# **EDUCATION**

**JUNE 2021** 

## MTECH, BITS PILANI

Pursuing MTech in Software Engineering with Distinction and zero backlogs.

#### **JULY 2017**

# BCA, MAHARAJA SURAJMAL INSTITUTE, NEW DELHI

Completed the bachelor's degree with Distinction and zero backlogs. Learned all the basic tools about how to program and innovating new things from the given tools.

#### **JUNE 2012**

HIGH SCHOOL, RICH HARVEST PUBLIC SCHOOL

# **PROJECTS**

## SAP RPA PROJECT — BOT TO READ INVOICE

Created an SAP RPA bot to read invoice from Outlook mail and upload invoice using UI5 or SAP GUI and send a success or failure mail to the admin.

## SMART AC PROJECT — ARDUINO AND RASPBERRY PI3 BASED.

An IoT project built on the Open Source platform Arduino to increase the usability of IR devices. The project was funded and Incubated by IIIT-Delhi.

## UI APP FOR STELLAR AWARD 2018 — UI5 APPS FOR STELLAR AWARDS JUDGES

Delivering UI5 apps for Participants nomination and winner selection for stellar awards. The 5 UI5 apps were delivered in a period of 1.5month and replacing the last used tool.

# **INTERESTS**

- Learn New Skills
- Touring and Exploring new places
- Know about new technologies